Kavish Hukmani

(650) 683-5325 ♦ kshukmani@ucdavis.edu ♦ San Francisco, CA ♦ LinkedIn ♦ GitHub ♦ Personal Website

PROFILE

Master of Science in Business Analytics candidate at UC Davis with 1 year of experience solving Machine Learning and Optimization problems at scale as a Data Scientist in a SaaS AI startup.

Specialties: Machine Learning, Data Analytics, Statistical Exploration, Optimization, Big Data, Computer Vision

Programming Languages: Python, SQL dialects (MySQL, BigQuery, MS SQL), R, Java

Technologies: Linux, Tableau, Gurobi, AWS, GCP, Advanced Excel, Git

Certifications: AWS Cloud Practitioner, Tableau Desktop Specialist, DeepLearning.AI Deep Learning Specialization

EDUCATION

University of California, Davis

San Francisco, CA

Master of Science, Business Analytics

Expected Jun. 2021

Highlighted Coursework: Machine Learning, Advanced Statistics, Big Data Analytics, Cloud Computing

Manipal Institute of Technology

Manipal, India

Bachelor of Technology, Major in Computer and Communication Engineering, Minor in Big Data

Aug. 2020

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Student Practicum: Angel Flight West

San Francisco, CA

Graduate Student Data Analyst

Oct. 2021 - Jun. 2022

As a part of the MSBA practicum, leveraged advanced analytics to help Angel Flight West, a non-profit organization that provides free non-emergency medical flights, double their reach.

- Saved over 500 flights a year from being canceled last minute by improving the accuracy of the flight cancellation risk assessment models using Azure ML.
- Used Google Analytics to analyze user drop-off in the new patient intake forms and conducted A/B tests to increase form completions.
- Performed ETL jobs on 5 years of flight data for ad-hoc analysis with SQL and Python.

Impact Analytics

Bengaluru, India

Data Scientist Aug. 2020 – Jun. 2021

Data Science Intern Jan. 2020 – Mar. 2020

Worked in the AI/Optimization team at Impact Analytics, a fast-growing startup providing SaaS solutions to retailers in the fashion and CPG markets.

- Enabled Tommy Hilfiger, Puma, and Calvin Klein to optimize their promotions and inventory allocation by building Linear Programming models in Gurobi. Reduced runtime by over 10x using heuristics.
- Trained a mobile vision CNN to identify image quality issues such as blur, tilt, and irrelevance.
- Maintained several critical APIs and servers used by client facing software.
- Helped develop a coupon book creator for a Fortune 500 warehouse club chain.

Daimler Financial Services India

Pune, India

Summer Intern (Digital & Marketing - Passenger Cars)

May. 2018 - Jul. 2018

Designed a chatbot using DialogFlow for the Mercedes-Benz Finance India social media pages.

PROJECTS

Solving Twisty Puzzles using Reinforcement Learning: Published a paper and accompanying open-source library

<u>DotA 2 Icon GAN</u>: Trained a GAN to generate new character skill icons for the video game DotA 2

Contributor to **D2ACQ**: An open-source online video game audio quiz

ADDITIONAL QUALIFICATIONS

Awards: MSBA Fellowship at UC Davis, Spot Award at Impact Analytics

Leadership: Core Committee Member and Head of Outstation Management for multiple college festivals.